<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<tracks>
<track>
  <title>Hero's Journey (Excerpt)</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <genre>composition</genre>
  <description>This is a track written about being a hero. Kind of quiet-like.</description>
  <url>audio/herosjourney.mp3</url>
  <tags>mysterious, anticipating, seeking, grooving, subtle, brazilian, dark, guitar, percussion, pad, piano</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Autobiographical Self</title>
  <genre>composition</genre>
  <genre>jazz</genre>
  <description>This is a piece written for a "young lion" jazz quartet. The kind of thing that is played best while wearing shades. Inspired, I thought, mostly by the idea of playing like Chris Potter with a njarka, until a friend pointed out a famous Beethoven fugue subject in there too. Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Take Toriyama - Drums, Gary Wang - Bass, Ethan Herr - piano.</description>
  <url>audio/autoselfmixdown.mp3</url>
  <tags>jazz, quartet, 5/4, time, modern, edgy, angular, composed through, njarka, beethoven, chris potter, piano, saxaphone</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Luce Chiara (last movement)</title>
  <genre>composition</genre>
  <description>This is part of a longer suite that I wrote for my wife. This last movement I just love, frankly.  Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Bass Clarinet, Gary Wang - Bass, Ethan Herr - piano.</description>
  <url>audio/lucechiara3.mp3</url>
  <tags>hindemith, bass, clarinet, piano, trio, arco, morning, major, poignant</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>What Clouds May Know</title>
  <genre>jazz</genre>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>Written back in college days, this one is inspired by views of intense cloud formations from rocky peaks. That and hormonal angst about a girl of course (my future wife in fact). It was also featured as a soundtrack on <![CDATA[<a href="http://vimeo.com/71941292" target="_blank">short film about covert photography</a>]]> by Stated Magazine. Lineup: Vinnie Sperrazza - Drums, Thomas Hogan - Bass, Ethan Herr - piano.</description>
  <url>audio/whatcloudsmayknow.mp3</url>
  <tags>jazz, straight, dark, spacious, trio, loop, drums, piano</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>No Exit</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <genre>jazz</genre>
  <description>A semi-free line inspired by a really cool sounding squeak of a large industrial door, with a "no exit" sign above it. Lineup: Vinnie Sperrazza - Drums, Thomas Hogan - Bass, Seth Trachey - Sax, Ethan Herr - piano.</description>
  <url>audio/noexit.mp3</url>
  <tags>jazz, fast, angular, free, improvisation, drums, quartet, saxaphone, piano</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>I Don't Know</title>
  <genre>jazz</genre>
  <description>Of all the laid back sambas I've written, this one is one of my favorites. Inspired by the feeling of wanting so badly to express something to someone, and finding that words just don't cut it.  Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Take Toriyama - Drums, Gary Wang - Bass, Ethan Herr - piano.</description>
  <url>audio/idontknow.mp3</url>
  <tags>jazz, brazillian, latin, samba, dark, bass flute, quartet, longing, quiet, brushes</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Paris</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>This is a piece about Paris. I've never been to Paris. But this is most likely the way I would feel about it, based on popular opinion, and other information.</description>
  <url>audio/paris.mp3</url>
  <tags>reflective, nostalgic, melancholic, pathetique, youth, memories, romantic, solo piano</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Farmers Son (Excerpt)</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>A little looping folky tune very much inspired by youthful summers spent at my grandparents farm in Lancaster PA.</description>
  <url>audio/farmersson.mp3</url>
  <tags>country, indie, reflective, nostalgic, guitar, rock, bill, frisell, farm</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>For Dad</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>From my earliest days playing with guitars. A song inspired by the song of the Golden-Crowned Sparrow, which, as a kid I very clearly remember my dad whistling along to while he painted in the living room.</description>
  <url>audio/fordad.mp3</url>
  <tags>country, reflective, golden, sparrow, bird, song, nostalgic, guitar, bill, frisell, youth</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>OK Conversation</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>A fun one that came to me while driving home after having what I though was a pretty "ok" conversation with one of my piano students. On a more interesting note, the percussion in this is me bashing away in a bathtub in about a half inch of water.</description>
  <url>audio/okconversation.mp3</url>
  <tags>african, swinging, happy, joy, water, guitar, piano, bathtub, guitar, marimba</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Home Boys</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>One of the few tunes I can honestly say wrote itself. Sat down after hanging out with a good friend, and there it was.</description>
  <url>audio/homeboys.mp3</url>
  <tags>home, folk, irish, melodic, happy, bright, bass, guitar</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Edgar</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>Inspired by Doc Watson, and a great sounding cheap old gas stove (played on with a fork). This just sounds like a dude named Edgar.</description>
  <url>audio/edgar.mp3</url>
  <tags>percussion, stove, country, bluegrass, happy, piano, bass, guitar</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Little Fish</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>A tune that would work great in a kid context. Or a fish context. Possibly a little one.</description>
  <url>audio/littlefish.mp3</url>
  <tags>cute, small, innocent, rhodes, marimba, happy, guitar</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Lover of My Life</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>Well, it's better than "Pizza Eating Lover", which was the original title, since that fit the melody. But the tone is serious, sweet, loving, and in the dark and lovely key of Db major.</description>
  <url>audio/loverofmylife.mp3</url>
  <tags>folk, rock, quiet, sweet, poignant, moving, piano, rhodes, bass, guitar</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>The Saints</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>An ode to living reclusively, seeking higher truth, prayer, and the emotional landscape of solitude.</description>
  <url>audio/thesaints.mp3</url>
  <tags>dark, prayer, concentration, solitude, inward, minor, percussion, 3/4, piano, guitar</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>Worlds of Orion</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>This was a little ditty written as background music for an educational video game for kids called <![CDATA[<a href="http://www.worldsoforion.com" target="_blank">Worlds of Orion</a>]]>.</description>
  <url>audio/worldsoforion.mp3</url>
  <tags>space, electronic, flowing, minimal, loop</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Waiting and Grooving</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>It's pretty much what the title is. Written for 'on hold' music for a design school, it's happy and makes you want to jiggle a little bit.</description>
  <url>audio/formaudio.mp3</url>
  <tags>hold, guitar, delay, ali, farka, african, background, waiting, grooving</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Stemcell Debate Theme</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>Theme music for a DVD series of stem cell debates at William Paterson University. There is something kind of cool about the sound of electronic music when each track is played manually.</description>
  <url>audio/stemcells.mp3</url>
  <tags>electronic, spacey, colors, shifting, background</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Media Reel</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>Written for a display of digital media work, this was my Aphex Twin inspired rendition of some tune sketches I had. Tune wise, I think I'm hearing echos of early Sting.</description>
  <url>audio/mediareel.mp3</url>
  <tags>electronic, drum, bass, dub, sting, aphex, twin</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Churchuary</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>Done for a video interview of a multimedia artist who liked to work in the basement of a church.</description>
  <url>audio/churchuary.mp3</url>
  <tags>electronic, dark, sanctuary, church, quiet, techno</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Havana</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>This was part of a larger work for a theater performance, Sonya Flew, co-composed with the late Chris Webb.</description>
  <url>audio/havana.mp3</url>
  <tags>latin, cuban, theater, piano, chris, webb, sonya, flew</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Toy Diddly</title>
  <genre>folk</genre>
  <description>Playing around with a Bo-Diddly groove on my son's toy guitar, I came up with this little number. I "matured" it a little bit with a slide, a strat, and some good old fashion tremolo.</description>
  <url>audio/toydiddly-upgraded.mp3</url>
  <tags>guitar, electric, slide, blues, tremolo, groove, bo-diddly, open, tuning, E, </tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Migrant</title>
  <genre>score</genre>
  <description>Inspired by a good friends report on the treatment of farm workers in California, and her years spent in Mexico. This one is currently waiting for a home.</description>
  <url>audio/migrant.mp3</url>
  <tags>mexican, spanish, migrant, farmers, labor, dark, sad, latin, piano, slow, ballad, minor</tags>
</track>
<track>
  <title>Prayer</title>
  <genre>jazz</genre>
  <description>A meditative exploration tetering between phrygian and lydian modes, with a lot of free form melodic improvisation, allusions to outer harmonic centers, and gamelan bells.</description>
  <url>audio/prayer.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, gamelan, bells, pedal, free, minor, meditation</tags>
</track>




<track>
  <title>Folk Song for Today</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>It was titled on the day it was written, but also applies to the larger "today". Imagine the late Miles quintet played through the lense of a shoegazer. Lineup: Ohad Talmor - Sax, Mark Small - Sax, Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Jaimeo Brown - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/folksongfortoday.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, bass, drums, sax, shoegazer</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>Hermetwo</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>My second ode to the great Hermeto Pascoal, with lot's of querky time changes that come directly out of the melody, as all time changes should. Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/hermetwo.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, bass, drums, sax, brazilian, bright, happy</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>Eb Minor Jazz</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>Some jazz in Eb minor. Lineup: Ohad Talmor - Sax, Mark Small - Sax, Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Jaimeo Brown - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/eflatminor.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, bass, drums, sax, groove, trashy</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>The Documents</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>As if they were found in the basement, after many years, and many trials and errors. Lineup: Ohad Talmor - Sax, Mark Small - Sax, Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Jaimeo Brown - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/thedocuments.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, bass, drums, sax</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>Changed Beach</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>This came directly out of a haunting dream I had of walking along a beach in Thailand after a tsunami and coming across a group of survivors in a ritual chant, aiding spirits to the afterlife. Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano/Noises</description>
  <url>edocs/changedbeach.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, bass, drums, sax, effects, pedal, prepared, chromatic, mallets</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>The Recital</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>Written for my Senior Recital, its kind of a mashup of sorts, even a bit overture-esk. Lineup: Ohad Talmor - Sax, Mark Small - Sax, Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Jaimeo Brown - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/therecital.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, bass, drums, sax, long, composed, straight</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>Poem for Driver and Listener</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>Written in the car while driving, one of the few times a melody came along uninhibited. Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/poem.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, sax, bass, drums, short, loop, free, irish, sweet, major</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>Andante</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>A semi-neo-classical clarinet feature written for Sam. Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Clarinet, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/andante.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, clarinet, bass, drums, effects, long, composed, minor, andante, scriabin</tags>
</track>

<track>
  <title>Circling</title>
  <genre>documents</genre>
  <description>Inspired by endlessly circling a piazza in Rome, late at night. Lineup: Sam Sadigursky - Sax, Chris VanVoorst - Bass, R.J. Miller - Drums, Ethan Herr - Piano</description>
  <url>edocs/circling.mp3</url>
  <tags>piano, sax, bass, drums, short, loop, wood, block, dark, poignant</tags>
</track>

</tracks>
